<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>grafana on Arco Research &amp; Documentation</title>
    <link>https://arcogroup.bitbucket.io/tags/grafana/</link>
    <description>Recent content in grafana on Arco Research &amp; Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 10:25:16 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://arcogroup.bitbucket.io/tags/grafana/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring System</title>
      <link>https://arcogroup.bitbucket.io/shapes/zigbee2mqtt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 10:25:16 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arcogroup.bitbucket.io/shapes/zigbee2mqtt/</guid>
      <description>Overview Zigbee2mqtt is an open-source project that enables the interconnection of different-brand devices with Zigbee connectivity. It can also be integrated with Home Assistant thanks to the bidirectional message relay from the network to MQTT. Because neither our Raspberry Pi nor our laptop has a ZigBee interface, we additionally need a zigbee adapter, this is the zig-a-zig-ah! (zzh!).
Ingredients In order to follow this recipe you will need:
 A suported Zigbee adapter (zzh!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating Xiaomi Mi Band 4 devices with smart mirror</title>
      <link>https://arcogroup.bitbucket.io/shapes/integrating_miband_with_smart_mirror/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 16:17:39 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arcogroup.bitbucket.io/shapes/integrating_miband_with_smart_mirror/</guid>
      <description>Overview Mi Band 4 is the most popular and best-selling smart band of the famous IT company Xiaomi. It provides several information about our physical activity like number of steps or heart rate. This device is linked with our smartphone, which access to its data using Bluetooth LE. Using this mechanism, and with a Raspberry Pi transformed into a smart mirror, we can monitorize this information and present it with graphs and other intuitive forms of displaying its progression through time.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
